- 需要帮忙吗? - 对
- Can I help you? - Uh, yeah. Um...
我想报案 流程是怎样的?
I would like to report something. How does it work?
你想报什么案?
What would you like to report?
我不知道该怎么跟你说 但我被人跟踪了
I don't know how to tell you this, but I'm, like, I'm getting stalked.
- 男人还是女人? - 一个女人
- By a man or a woman? - A woman.
你们有过性关系吗?
Have you had a sexual relationship with this woman?
没有 她年纪比我大
No, I... I haven't. She's a bit older than me.
年龄通常不是我们考虑的因素
Age is generally not a factor we consider.
不 当然 但我可以保证 绝对没有跟她发生过关系
No, of course. I can assure you, though, I... I absolutely haven't.
好吧 你说这个女人在跟踪你?
Okay. You say this woman's stalking you?
对 她总去我工作的地方、去我家
Yeah. She comes to my work. She comes to my house.
而且一直给我发邮件
She sends me emails, like... like all the time.
内容有威胁性吗?
Are any threatening towards ya?
喔 绝对有 我随便找一封出来给你看 这个
Oh, I'm sure. I mean... I mean, let me just open up a random one. Here.
我刚吃了一个蛋
我不认为这具有任何威胁性
I wouldn't say that's particularly threatening.
她真的发过有威胁性的邮件
They're... they're in here somewhere.
只是我得把它们筛选出来...
I just need to sift through all of the...
听着 我真的很担心
Look, I'm... I'm really worried here.
我觉得她需要帮助
I think she needs help.
这种情况持续多久了?
How long has it been going on?
我没算过
I don't know, like...
大概六个月吧
six months, maybe.
六个月?
Six months?!
那你为什么现在才来报案?
Why'd it take you so long to report it?
这是一个真实的故事
起初我为她感到难过
I felt sorry for her.
那是我第一眼的直觉
That's the first feeling I felt.
可怜一个初次见到的人
It's a patronizing, arrogant feeling,
这种想法未免有些自大和高高在上
feeling sorry for someone you've only just laid eyes on,
但我真是这么想的 我为她感到难过
but I did. I felt sorry for her.
- 去招呼客人 傻冒 - 好 抱歉
- Serve, you twat. - Yep. Sorry.
五英镑 谢谢
Fiver, please, mate.
- 谢了 伙计 谢谢 - 多谢
- Cheers, mate. Thank you. - Thanks.
- 您想要点什么吗? - 不了 谢谢
- Can I get you something? - No, thanks.
您确定吗?
Are you sure?
- 喝杯茶? - 不用了 谢谢
- Cup of tea? - No, thanks.
- 要坐在店里 您得消费 - 我什么也买不起
- You have to buy something. - Can't afford something.
- 是吗 连一杯茶也买不起? - 对
- Right. Not even a cup of tea? - No.
好吧 那...
Right, well...
要不我免费给您一杯茶吧
How about I give you a cup of tea on the house?
好的
All right.
- 你是做什么工作的? - 我是律师
- So, what do you do? - I'm a lawyer.
你是怎么当上律师的?
How'd you get into that, then?
我接受过刑法培训
I trained in criminal law,
后来我搬去了英格兰 再次受训后开办了自己的律所
moved to England, retrained, opened up my own practice,
赢得了几个奖项 现在是政府的一名首席顾问
won several awards, now a leading advisor to the government.
- 你有自己的律所? - 不止
- You own a law firm? - Amongst other things.
我有三套公寓 皮姆利科那套能俯瞰私人花园
A flat in Pimlico overlooking a private garden,
贝克斯利希斯一套 贝尔塞斯公园两套
one in Bexleyheath, two in Belsize Park.
上帝不喜人炫耀
God doesn't like a bragger,
但身为顶级政客的首席法律顾问
but when you're the go-to for the biggest political minds,
自然有资格炫耀
you've earned a brag or two.
不 我不会告诉你 客户的名字 所以别问
No, no, I'm not gonna say who, so don't even go there.
好吧
Fine!
戴维·卡梅伦、尼克·克莱格 亚历克斯·萨尔蒙德 但你当我没说
David Cameron, Nick Clegg, Alex Salmond. But you didn't hear that from me.
奈杰尔·法拉奇 托尼·布莱尔
哇 那你一定参加过很高端的晚宴吧
Wow. You must have amazing dinner parties.
她的笑声很不可思议 如此飘飘然 又有点令人不安
She had this incredible laugh. This giddy, slightly disconcerting laugh.
- 她的名字叫... - 玛莎
- Her name was... - Martha.
但我满脑子只想着 若这些都是真的
But all I could think was, if all of this is true,
你怎么会连杯茶都买不起?
then why can't you afford a cup of tea?
我许要一个好男孩莱照顾我 他要长得像只驯鹿宝贝一样
从我的iPhone发送
驯鹿宝贝
我搬到伦敦是为了 实现毕生的梦想 成为一名谐星
I'd moved to London to fulfil my lifelong dream of becoming a comedian,
但不知怎地 我年近三十 却仍干着毫无晋升空间的工作
but for whatever reason found myself late twenties, working a dead-end job
免费住在前女友的妈妈
and living rent-free with my ex-girlfriend's mother
位于偏远郊区的大房子里
in a massive house miles out of town.
初来乍到时 我怀揣着雄心壮志
I had arrived with such grand plans to be someone,
仿佛我这些一塌糊涂的滑稽笑料
as though my brand of wacky, bullshit comedy
正是这座国际大都市缺少的奇思妙想
was exactly what this world-leading city was missing.
我最近改吃素了
So I went vegan recently.
不得不做出些牺牲
Had to make some sacrifices.
这是貂皮帽
It's a mink hat.
但它不是用貂皮做的 而是一顶寻常帽子上订了只貂
But instead of actual mink, it's a mink stapled to a hat.
你弱爆了
You're shite!
见鬼
Fucking hell.
但伦敦就是这样 它不会张开双臂迎接任何人
But that's the thing with London. It red-carpets for no one.
感觉就像某天醒来 忽然发现自己只是茫茫人海中
It's like waking up one day to find yourself a background artist
一个渺小的背景板
in a cast of millions.
所以当有人透过那现实的泥潭
So when someone sees you through the mire of it all,
看到了你梦想成为的自己
sees you as the person you came here to be,
你自然会注意到她
you notice them.
你会注意到她看到了你
You notice them noticing you.
现在玛莎每天都会来店里
Every day now, Martha would come in,
每次都会换上全新的妆容和发型 如同在玩装扮游戏的孩子
each time with new makeup, new hairstyles, like a kid playing dress-up.
她的开场白总是...
She always opened the conversation by saying...
我很快就得走了
I've gotta go.
...但却总会一直待到我下班
...but then would stick around for the entire shift.
我认为她此举很奇怪 把自己粉饰成一个大忙人
I always thought it was strange that she painted herself as a busy person,
好像这样我就不会看穿
as though she could trick me
她其实根本无所事事
into thinking she's not spending all of her time hanging around.
今天很忙 有年度股东大会和股东会议要赶
Got a busy day today. AGMs, shareholder meets.
然后还得去理发 所以我不能聊太久
Then I'm getting my hair buffed, so can't chat long.
她每次都点同样的饮料 一杯...
She always ordered the same drink every time. A...
健怡可乐 多加冰
Diet Coke. Plenty ice.
我总是免费供应
I always gave it to her on the house.
- 但她从来不喝 - 我在代表一些大客户...
- She never drank her drink. - I'm representing big clients...
只是机械性地坐在那里
Instead, she would sit there on autopilot,
滔滔不绝地谈论她生活中的大人物
monologuing breathlessly about people in her life
但从来不说他们究竟是谁
without ever explaining who they were.
我先前在跟史蒂夫聊天
I was talking to Steve earlier.
我刚才在跟朱恩聊天 先前在跟艾伦通电话
I was chatting to Joan. Alan was on the phone.
就像我早知道这些人是谁 我是她的老熟人似的
Like I knew them already. Like I was already a part of her life.
当她不谈论那些人
And when she wasn't speaking about them
或者她的律所和她认识的大名人时
or her law firm or all the famous people she knew,
她会坐在那里谈论我
she would sit there talking about me.
你的手很有男子气概呢
You've got really manly hands, haven't you?
- 是吗? - 浑厚深沉的嗓音 轮廓分明的下颌线
- Oh yeah? - Big, deep voice. Chiseled jawline.
你这样完美的骨相简直违法嘛
Should be illegal to have your bone structure too.
他们真该向你收税 男人税
They should tax you for it. Man tax.
她的一切都让我好奇
Everything about her intrigued me.
她那无穷的自信、奇怪的说话方式
Her endless confidence, her weird turn of phrase,
以及在高谈阔论之余 偶尔展露的诗意
the surprising poetry that slipped through the cracks of her madness.
我们一起逃离这城市的喧嚣吧
Shall we run away together?
我的生日快到了 想做点特别的事
My birthday's coming up. Want to do something spesh.
谁说我想逃了?
Who says I wanna run away?
你已经在逃了 有些人想逃避时 会收拾行囊
You're already doing it. Some people run away by packing their bags.
而有些人会在同一个地方 长久地裹足不前
Others run away by standing in the same place for too long.
抱歉
Sorry.
我今早起来就感觉不对劲 不知道我这是怎么了
Woke up a little gravy this morning. Not sure what's come over me.
在她最脆弱的时刻 我会看着她
Then I would look at her in her most vulnerable moments,
开始重新想象她的过去
and I would start to reimagine her past.
没人邀请她去学校舞会
The school balls that no one took her to.
她自娱自乐 无数次地试穿婚纱
The time she tried on wedding dresses for fun.
以及许多个夜晚
Nights lost on social media
她沉浸在社交媒体上 浏览富人和名流的生活
perusing the lives of the rich and famous.
不知我当时是怎么想的 竟开始鬼使神差地赞美她
So I don't know what it was in me, but I started paying her compliments.
你的生日快到了 21岁生日吗?
Your birthday's coming up. Your 21st, is it?
我都42岁了
I'm 42!
四十二? 完全看不出来 你是冻龄女神吗?
You're 42? Well, you'd better give Peter Pan his moisturizer back.
天哪
My oh my!
你这小嘴是抹了蜜吗? 淘气鬼
You've got a silver tongue on you, you do, devil boy.
我可以教你用它做更妙的事情
Wouldn't mind teaching you where to put it.
这周末一起去野餐吧? 为我庆生
What do you say to picnic fun times this weekend to celebrate?
艳阳高照 花粉量也低
The sun's out. Pollen count's low.
你可以做个天然美黑 还不用担心过敏
You can get a tan without getting the sniffles.
好啊 我和你去野餐
Sure, I'll come picnic with you.
天啊
Oh my!
和我最喜欢的驯鹿宝贝一起野餐
Picnic fun times with my favorite reindeer.
把手机号给我 我们好一起筹划
Give me your number. We can arrange.
这样吧
Tell you what,
告诉我时间和地点 我们到时候见
name the time and the place, and I'll get you there.
我会站在那个美丽的黑发女郎身边
I'll be the one next to the gorgeous brunette.
哪个黑发女郎?
Who's that, then?
噢 你是说我吗?
Oh! You mean me?
我开始爱上了她的笑声 我迷恋那声音
I began to love her laugh, obsess with it,
以至不遗余力地逗她开心
do everything I could to eke it out of her.
都是些随意 无害的俏皮话
It was casual. It was harmless.
但我们的关系逐渐成了酒吧里的谈资
It was becoming a joke around the bar.
喂 唐尼 你不给我们介绍一下你女朋友吗?
Oi, Donny. Aren't you gonna introduce us to your girlfriend?
这就是你一直跟我们说的美女?
So is this the one you've been telling us about?
- 那个超模? - 你说我是超模? 真的吗?
- The supermodel? - You said that? Really?
拜托 唐尼 别藏着掖着了 你们俩打算什么时候上床?
Yeah, so come on, Donny. Out with it. When are you two gonna shag?
我不认同婚前性行为
Ah, don't believe in sex before marriage.
那你还等什么?
What you waiting for?
求婚啊
Ask her.
对呀 求婚
Yeah. Ask her!
求婚
Ask her! ...
怎么 开不了口吗?
What, you not asking?
我会是个好老婆哦
I'm marriage material.
光一半财产就够你暴富了
Half of everything makes you rich.
刚买了一套顶层公寓 家具齐全的
Just bought a penthouse. Furnished.
现在就差一个人帮我挂窗帘了
All I need now is for someone to hang my curtains.
"帮她挂窗帘"
"Hang her curtains."
不知怎地听起来有点色情
Something about it sounded vaguely sexual.
我讨厌把自己拉低到跟他们同一水平
I hated lowering myself to their level,
但我需要化解这令人尴尬至极的局面
but I needed a way out of that painfully awkward situation.
好啊 那我就满足你的需求
I'll hang your curtains!
我想逗她笑
I wanted her to laugh.
我希望她对这个玩笑 一笑了之 但她没有
I wanted her to share in the joke, but she just didn't.
那一刻 我意识到
I knew then, in that moment,
她把那句话当真了
that she'd taken it seriously.
驯鹿宝贝 玫瑰太俗套了 你要响些有创意的点子追我
我能一口气高潮好几次哦
我回教你各种手上工夫
我得走了 -小玛
从我的iPhone发送
然后我开始收到她的邮件
Then came her emails,
一天差不多80封 从早发到晚
around 80 a day, continuing long into the night.
垃圾邮件
她的账户名跟垃圾邮件一样 是一串随机组合的数字和字母
Her address, a random series of numbers and letters, like spam,
但内容跟她的说话风格如出一辙
but the writing, exactly like she spoke.
不经大脑、直白露骨
Unhesitating, unfiltered.
恬不知耻地赤裸裸
Unapologetically raw.
有很多简单的字都写错了 而一些复杂的字
There were spelling errors on words much simpler to spell
却都能写对
than other words she spelled perfectly.
原来她有一部苹果手机
The fact she has an iPhone,
但我在酒吧 从来没见过她用苹果手机发短信
even though she didn't when I saw her texting at the bar.
看我带来了什么 小驯鹿
Look what I got, reindeer,
为我们的快乐野餐准备的
ahead of picnic fun times.
嗒哒 一个小食篮
Ta-da! A wee-willie hamper.
里面有果酱、橘子酱
It's got jam and marmalade,
香煎面包块
croutons,
还有香槟呢 如果你爱喝酒的话
and champagne, too, if that's your tipple.
我不喝酒 但我不介意你把它
I don't drink myself, but you're absolutely welcome
倒在我的胸上舔舐享用
to pour it on my chest and lick it from me.
经典食篮 195.5英镑
怎么了?
What's the matter?
没什么 只是你未免太破费了吧
No, nothing. It's just you've... you've spent quite a lot here.
今年的生日很特别
Well, it's a special birthday this year.
是我的43岁生日呢
My 43rd, no less.
而且可以和你一起度过
And I get to spend it with you.
玛莎 我觉得这不是一个好主意
Martha, I think maybe this isn't such a great idea.
什么? 你不想野餐了吗?
What? No picnic fun times?
对 我不想去
No, I... I don't think so.
真的吗? 为什么? 我刚还去买了一床被单呢
Really? Why? I've just gone and bought a quilt too.
很柔软的 这样你躺在草地上就不会长疹子了
It's extra soft so you don't get pimples from the grass.
说到野餐 应该是情侣才会一起做的事吧?
Well, picnics, that's... that's kind of what lovers do, you know?
那朋友会做什么?
Well, what do friends do?
- 不知道 喝杯咖啡之类的吧 - 咖啡很好呀
- I don't know. A coffee or something. - Coffee's good.
咖啡欢乐时光 耶
我叉点就给你买丁字裤了 但转念一响 我又不是小女生
不需要那玩意莱调情 狠狠干我吧!
从我的iPhone发送
全天菜单
- 你想好要吃什么了吗? - 我想要苏格兰浓汤
- Do you know what you're having? - Well, I want the Scotch broth.
不知道有没有戏
Trying to figure out if it's on the menu or not.
我在菜单上没看...
I don't see it on the m--
一语双关啊 厉害
Oh. Very good.
所以呢? 有戏吗?
Well? Is it on the menu?
很遗憾 没有
Uh, no, I'm afraid not.
不过今日特供可以有
You'll find it in the specials though.
今日特供
The specials.
你笑得好夸张
that is some laugh.
是啊 大家总这么说
Yeah, I get that all the time.
笑笑妞 我爸以前总这么叫我
Chuckles Buckles, my dad used to call me.
他那双手可大了
With his big hands.
好吧 笑笑妞 你有音量旋钮吗? 能不能调低一点?
Well, do you have a volume dial? Can I turn you down a bit?
那你得先让我性奋起来
You'd have to turn me on first.
你对我是认真的吗?
So, are you serious about me?
实话实说吧 我能承受
I can take it. Just be honest.
我负责过不少世界级的大案子
I mean, I've overseen some of the biggest cases in the world.
好莱坞、任何你能想到的业界大拿
Hollywood. You name it.
我什么都能应付
I can handle anything.
但很遗憾 显然 你那些关于"满足我"的言语
Be a shame though, obviously, what with the... with the curtains,
勾起了我的期待
getting my hopes up.
但我会收拾好心情的
But I'd work through it.
我会想办法释怀
I'd work through it.
我对你是认真的
Yes, I'm... I'm... I'm serious about you.
不 别叫唤 天哪
No, don't! Oh my God.
慢着 是朋友 好吗?  我把你当朋友
Wait. As a friend, okay? As a friend.
朋友
Friends
会上床的那种
with benefits.
只是普通朋友
Just friends.
- 请问你们要点餐吗? - 是的
- Can I get you guys anything? - Uh, yeah.
- 我要一杯美式咖啡 谢谢 - 好
- I'll have an Americano, please. - Yep.
- 给我一杯自来水就好 - 当然
- I'll just have a tap water. Sure.
- 你什么都不吃? - 我吃不起
- Uh, you're not having anything? - I can't afford it.
我给你买单 就...
I'll get it. Just...
好
Oh. Okay.
我要一份羊角面包、一份燕麦甜饼
Uh, can I have a croissant, a flapjack,
一个巧克力布朗尼和一杯咖啡
and a chocolate brownie and a coffee?
好的 请问您要哪种咖啡?
Sure. What kind of coffee?
脱因咖啡 好的 我这就去为您取餐 谢谢
Decaf. Perfect. I'll grab those for you now. Thanks.
那个... 你是怎么知道我的邮件地址的?
So, um, how did you get my email?
在你网站上找到的
Oh. Off your website.
你不该把它写上去 随便一个路人甲都能看到
You shouldn't have it on there. Any so-and-so could get it.
- 我开始意识到了 - 所以你是一名谐星?
- Yeah, I'm starting to realize that. - So you're a comedian?
- 算是吧 - 事业进展不顺
- Sort of. - It's not going well.
你是在问我吗?
Is that a question?
不 这种事我看得出来 你的事业不顺
No. I can tell these things. It's not going well.
其实并没有 所以...
That's not true, actually, so--
我在网上看过你的视频了 那些笑话很烂
I saw some of your comedy videos online. I thought they were shite.
- 我现在有进步了 - 用词也更冒犯人了
- Well, I've moved on a bit now. - Offensive too.
- 那叫讽刺 - 拙劣的讽刺
- It's satire. - Thin satire.
不好意思 你是评论家吗?
Sorry, are you a critic?
- 您的餐点 - 谢谢
Here you are. - Oh. Thank you.
听着 玛莎
Listen, Martha.
你能不能答应我 别跟酒吧里的人说
Can you promise me you won't tell anyone at the pub
我网上那些视频的事?
about those online videos?
别闹了 你该感到自豪才对
Stop it! You should be proud.
你在追逐自己的梦想
You're chasing your dreams.
对 不 我明白 只是...
Yeah, no, I get that. It's just...
只是什么?
What is it?
我这辈子都梦想着成为谐星 只是我...
I spent my life dreaming of becoming a comedian. I just...
我没想到这条路这么难走
I didn't realize it was gonna be so fucking hard.
宝剑锋从磨砺出 不是吗?
Hardness can be good though, too, no?
对 我知道 只是...
Yeah, I know. It's just...
我...我以前总认为 追逐梦想终将收获快乐 但是...
I, like... I used to think my dreams would lead to happiness, but...
现在我感觉这二者并不可兼得
now it almost feels like this choice between the two.
有人伤害了你 对吧?
Somebody hurt you, didn't they?
我能看出来
I can tell.
你就像一位战士
You're like a warrior
铠甲上裂开了一道口子
with a chink in the armor.
像是某种伤痕
Like a wounding of some kind.
那是个女人吗?
Was it a woman?
你失恋了?
A heartbreak?
不 我没事
No, I'm fine.
战士就是这么嘴硬
That's what a warrior would say.
但我看得出来 你的心在流血
But I can see you're bleeding.
你被伤得很深
Deep wounds.
是谁伤害了你?
Who was it?
玛莎 你能放开我的手吗?
Martha, can you let go of my hand now, please?
- 告诉我她的名字 - 玛莎 拜托
- I want names. Martha, please.
名字
Names.
- 玛莎 请你放手 - 名字
- Martha, please. Names.
- 玛莎 求你了 放手 - 你竟敢如此放肆
Martha, please, let go! - Don't! Don't you dare!
一切还好吗?
Is everything all right here?
是的 我们没事
yeah, we're fine.
真的没事
We're... we're fine. Honest.
你们还想要些什么吗?
Can I get you guys anything else, or...
我想买单
Just the bill.
- 你走哪条路? - 这边
- What way are you walking? - Uh, this way.
我走这边
I'm this way.
谢谢你请我吃布朗尼
Thanks for the brownie.
我知道她不是身家百万的律师
I knew she wasn't a millionaire lawyer,
但她那番疯狂的举动 令我隐隐有些不安
but seeing her madness play out like that left me with this sense of unease.
这女人是谁 她究竟看上了我什么?
Who was this woman, and what did she see in me?
见鬼 可恶
Fuck! Shit!
驯鹿宝贝 我发现你在偷看了 小偷窥狂
从我的iPhone发送
有时我会怀疑 如果那天没有跟踪她
I sometimes question what would have happened had I not followed her,
而是直接回家
just turned around and went home.
这场噩梦会不会早就结束了
Whether that is where this whole ordeal might have ended.
也许内心深处 我想被发现
Maybe some part of me wanted to get caught.
也许内心深处 我想看事情会发展成什么样
Maybe some part of me wanted to see where it all might take me.
好的 各位 到目前为止 本场比赛真是精彩纷呈
Okay, guys, it's been a fantastic competition so far.
诸多表演者竞相角逐半决赛的席位
Loads of acts vying for a place in the semifinals.
希望大家保持这份活力 有请下一位表演者
Keep that energy up, and please welcome to the stage,
唐尼·邓恩登场
your next act, Donny Dunn!
好的 好了 请容我先把箱子放下 很快就好
Okay! Good. All right, let me just quickly chuck this down.
做好演出的准备
Ooh. Set up the gig.
拉开这旧行李箱的拉链
Just unzip the old bagarooney.
好的 搞定
Okay, good. Woo!
好了
All right. Ooh.
砰 对 好的 好
Bang! Yes. All right. Cool.
这真是...
That's...
我知道你们在想什么
Now, I know what you're thinking.
男版维纳斯·威廉姆斯放飞自我了
Venus Williams has let herself go.
抱歉 天啊 我说错名字了 抱歉 这是我新想出来的笑料
Oh, sorry. God, no. I said the wrong name. Sorry, it's new material.
容我拿笔记本看看 然后我...
I'll just grab my notebook out, and I'll...
我再重说一遍 好的 那就...找到了
I'll do it again. Okay, let's just... Here it is. Ha.
我知道你们在想什么
So I know what you're thinking.
男版塞雷娜·威廉姆斯放飞自我了
Serena Williams has let herself go.
好吧 这不好笑 那我们换个话题
Okay, cool. That didn't work. Let's move on.
有一位笑了 希望你的快乐能感染在座的其他人
Uh, one laugh. If you could move around the room, that'd be great.
真是去哪都不能带上我妈呀
Jesus, can't take my mum anywhere, eh?
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
玛莎
Martha.
你好 玛莎 你把宇宙飞船停在外面了吗?
Hello, Martha. Is your spaceship parked outside?
对 在外面
Yeah, outside.
想兜兜风 跟我回我的母星吗?
Want to go for a ride back to my home planet?
你的母星? 那个星球上的人会觉得我搞笑吗?
Your home planet? A planet where people find me funnier?
我要去
I'm sold!
你的母星在哪里?
And where is your home planet?
贝尔塞斯公园
Belsize Park.
那我很好奇 你说的宇宙飞船是指...
and so, out of interest, when you say your spaceship, you mean...
一辆菲亚特鹏托
A Fiat Punto.
很精彩 女士们先生们 这个梗真是绝了
Brilliant. Ladies and gentlemen, it ain't gonna get much better than that.
天啊
Jesus, Jesus.
拜托 好吧 那...
Come on. All right, so, you know--
我会唱歌 知道吗?
I can sing, you know?
大家不是来这儿听歌的 所以...
Oh, well, people haven't come here for singing, so...
让她唱
let her sing!
- 来吧 让她唱 - 不行
Go on! Let her sing! No.
拜托 让她唱几句
Come on, let her sing! Let her sing!
好吧 行 真是被你们打败了
Okay, fine, sod it. Go on, then.
那你唱吧
Wahey! Whoo!
♪ 我知道要排队等待 直到你认为有时间 ♪
♪ I know I stand in line Until you think you have the time ♪
♪ 陪我共度一晚 ♪
♪ To spend an evening with me... ♪
南茜·辛纳特拉 你怎么跑这儿来了?
Nancy Sinatra, what the hell are you doing here?
♪ 哪怕你我去某处跳舞 我也知道有可能 ♪
♪ And if we go someplace to dance I know that there's a chance ♪
♪ 你会独自离去 ♪
♪ You won't be leaving with me ♪
你会唱活结乐队的歌吗?
Do you know any Slipknot?
我也想让你多唱会儿 但恐怕你会盖过我的风头
I would let you sing more, but can't handle you upstaging me.
请大家给玛莎一点掌声 对
A round of applause for Martha, everyone. Yes!
太棒了
Ha-ha! Brilliant.
好极了 很好
Absolutely brilliant. Cool.
其实我一直觉得那首歌很奇怪
I've always thought that song was really weird, actually.
他们可能真会说出一些很蠢的话
They could have said something really stupid like,
"然后我把气氛全搞砸了 我说了这样的傻话
"Then I go and spoil it all by saying something stupid like,
'世人误解了希特勒'"
'Hitler was misunderstood.'"
我最近改吃素了
So I went vegan recently.
不得不做出些牺牲
Had to make some sacrifices.
因为我交了新女友 她可是货真价实的弹簧鸡 拜托!
Met a new girlfriend. She's a real spring chicken. Come on!
她嘴上功夫可好了 糟糕 头掉了
Yep, gives great head. Oh no, no, no, no, no.
好啊 我们都进入状态了
Good. We're rocking and rolling. Good, good.
你戴那顶水貂帽时 不知未何 我敢觉你在发光
从我的iPhone发送
见鬼
Fucking hell.
你是怎么做到的?
How'd you do that?
- 什么? - 忽然出现
- What? - Just appear.
你就像...忍者猫一样
You're like... Ninja Cat.
你今晚的段子很搞笑 赢得当之无愧
That was fun stuff tonight. You deserved your win.
比网上那破视频好多了
Better than that shit online.
那就谢谢夸奖了
Thanks, I think.
你那些道具和小玩意什么的
All the props and the gadgets and stuff.
太好玩了 驯鹿宝贝
So funny, reindeer.
你是天生的喜剧人 不是吗?
You have it in your bones, this comedy lark, don't you?
谢谢
Thank you.
噢 别谢我
Oh, don't thank me.
你该感谢自己
Thank yourself.
感谢你的天赋
Thank your bones.
听着
Look.
关于昨天我在你家外面的事
About yesterday, when I was outside.
对不起 我不该跟踪你的
I shouldn't have followed you. I was--
噢 别傻了
Oh, no, don't be silly.
我才不会气你偷看呢
I don't begrudge you a peep.
下回直接进来吃大餐吧
Just come in for a plate next time.
我会为你献上我的特色菜
I'll cook you my special dish.
你的特色菜是什么?
What's your special dish?
肥美的小穴
Beef curtains.
见鬼
Fucking hell.
你真的很疯 知道吗?
You're utterly mad, aren't you?
如果能拥有超能力 你希望它是什么?
If you had a superpower, what would it be?
我希望能听见人们的心声
I'd wanna know what people were thinking,
那我就不用一直猜测了
rather than just guessing all the time.
什么? 你担心人们觉得你不好吗?
What? Are you worried people think bad of you or something?
不 我担心人们压根不把我放在眼里
No. I'm worried they don't think about me at all.
- 我想要的超能力很奇怪 - 正如我所料
- Mine's weird. - I expect nothing less.
你有没有幻想过
Do you ever, like,
拉开某人的拉链
want to unzip people
爬进他们的身体?
and climb inside them?
我通常不会有这种冲动 没有
Can't say it's an impulse I've had very often, no.
我希望人类在下巴上有拉链
I wish humans had a chin zip.
可以往下一直拉开到肚子上
One that would open all the way to their bellies.
那我就能拉开拉链 舒服地钻进去
I'd just unzip them and tuck myself away.
你这是想拿我当人皮大衣吗?
Is this you asking me for my skin suit?
对 我要把你当连体服穿
Yes, I'd wear you like a onesie.
天哪 依偎在你的身体里 度过一整个冬天
Oh my God. Snuggle away inside you all winter.
那感觉一定很棒
Ah, that'd be nice.
但我会想念饼干的
I'd miss biscuits though.
那这么着吧
Well, um, I tell you what,
写一张单子 列出你喜欢的饼干
give me a list of the ones you like,
我会趁没人注意 时不时地
and every now and again, when nobody's looking,
拉开下巴上的拉链 扔几块饼干进去给你
I'll unzip my chin and pop some biscuits inside for you.
听起来怎么样?
How does that sound?
那就两全其美了 天哪
Best of both worlds! Oh my God.
天啊
Oh my God.
你这小嘴可真会说话
The tongue on you.
♪ 然后我们来到一个安静的小地方 ♪
♪ And afterwards we drop Into a quiet little place ♪
♪ 小酌一两杯 ♪
♪ And have a drink or two... ♪
♪ 然后我把气氛全搞砸了 我说了这样的傻话 ♪
♪ And then I go and spoil it all By saying something stupid like ♪
- 世人误解了希特勒 - ♪ 我爱你 ♪
-"Hitler was misunderstood." - ♪ I love you ♪
我爱你
I love you.
不
Oh no.
- 是朋友之爱 就像你说的 - 对 不
- As a friend. Like you said. - Yeah. No.
- 抱歉 - 我说太多了 是吧?
- Sorry. - I've said too much, haven't I?
天哪 这该死的不听使唤的笨嘴
Oh my God. Stupid. Stupid fucking moron gob!
- 不 你别这样 好吗? - 笨蛋!
No, no, don't do that, okay? Don't do that.
没事的 好吧? 别这样 好吗? 拜托 你...
It's fine, all right? It's fine. Don't do that, okay? Please, just...
我隐约觉得 你会是我的劫数
I have a sneaky feeling you might be the death of me.
拉下去
Z-z-z-z-zip.
好友申请 玛莎·史考特
戴维·卡梅伦 致 玛莎·史考特 再次多亏你力挽狂澜!
没了我他会失去方向的
我今天遇见了一个人
属于我的驯鹿宝贝 我要跟他长厢厮守
玛莎·史考特律师
变态跟踪狂
律师被吊销执照
连环跟踪狂被判刑
我在电脑前坐了好几个小时查阅资料
I sat there for hours taking it all in.
拼凑她的整个人生轨迹
Piecing together her whole timeline.
她参加的毕业生计划 她因对老板的不当行为而被解雇
Her graduate job. How she got fired for inappropriate behavior with the boss.
她开始在他家附近徘徊
How she started hanging around outside his house,
然后对警方诬告他虐待他的残障小孩
then falsely reporting him to the police for abusing his disabled child.
还有一次 她在街上攻击他的母亲
This other time she attacked his mother in the street.
她被判过四年半监禁
Her four-and-a-half-year prison sentence.
我被一个已经定罪的跟踪狂盯上了
I had a convicted stalker stalking me.
已添加好友
根据理查德·加德的话剧 《驯鹿宝贝》改编